<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: An Interview With Memeber Of Ecovillage</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.russellheimlich.com/blog/an-interview-with-memeber-of-ecovillage/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.russellheimlich.com/blog/an-interview-with-memeber-of-ecovillage/</link>
	<description>The Blog of Russell Heimlich</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 14:13:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: Stephanie Backs</title>
		<link>http://www.russellheimlich.com/blog/an-interview-with-memeber-of-ecovillage/comment-page-1/#comment-2330</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stephanie Backs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 05:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.russellheimlich.com/blog/an-interview-with-memeber-of-ecovillage/#comment-2330</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Was that a cob shower in the last photo?!? I&#039;m a Canadian student and thinking of building a small cob house (100sq feet, so no building codes required) in my parents yard so I can live independently, sustainably, and not have to pay rent in god aweful student houses. So far the plans include an outhouse, but the shower is the issue. How did you water proof it? How did you set up the drain within the dirt floor? Please contact me any information helps!]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Was that a cob shower in the last photo?!? I&#8217;m a Canadian student and thinking of building a small cob house (100sq feet, so no building codes required) in my parents yard so I can live independently, sustainably, and not have to pay rent in god aweful student houses. So far the plans include an outhouse, but the shower is the issue. How did you water proof it? How did you set up the drain within the dirt floor? Please contact me any information helps!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: Uncle B</title>
		<link>http://www.russellheimlich.com/blog/an-interview-with-memeber-of-ecovillage/comment-page-1/#comment-1421</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Uncle B]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 20:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.russellheimlich.com/blog/an-interview-with-memeber-of-ecovillage/#comment-1421</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ecovillage folk are on the right track! The Asian Fact: the burgeoning Asian demands, for a larger share of the finite world&#039;s resources will mean an unwelcome sharing by Americans, their dollar no longer strong enough to command the 80% of world&#039;s finite Resources to maintain their current unsustainable &quot;Status Quo&quot; is being beaten out of international marketplaces by a strong Chinese Yuan as we speak! Oil is next to go! China has acquired the &quot;South Azadegan Oil fields&quot; from Iran! This is the largest Oil discovery in thirty years in the Middle East! It did not go to war-like American interests at all! Asians bid for oil world -round and well outside the American admonition that only American dollars be used for oil in the world! The Russians, Chavez and others resent this &quot;Manipulation&quot; of oil prices enough to go to war over it. World conditions have changed, even for Yankee Doodle! See: http://uprooted.jessicareeder.com/2009/09/detroit-and-the-100-dollar-house/comment-page-1/#comment-3003
http://www.marchandmeffre.com/detroit/index.html
to find out what happened to &quot;Motor City U.S.A.&quot;  when cheaper Chinese parts in Japanese , Korean and other imported cars were let loose on the American home-markets! China in fact, exports food to the U.S.A.! India mans our computer services by satellite! they send us engineers and do our computer engineering at home in India for us! The Asian onslaught of the larger boned heavier higher calorie, high salary, high upkeep, American is just beginning! The easy resources in America are all gone and we have to change our ways to survive, and this paradigm shift will not be painless! We are about to get our great fattened asses whittled down to size by a very cunning, well educated Asian population, they are at the forefront of change in America, even causing it from their own lands where we cannot do battle with them! The world has shifted, and America is part of the change like it or not.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ecovillage folk are on the right track! The Asian Fact: the burgeoning Asian demands, for a larger share of the finite world&#8217;s resources will mean an unwelcome sharing by Americans, their dollar no longer strong enough to command the 80% of world&#8217;s finite Resources to maintain their current unsustainable &#8220;Status Quo&#8221; is being beaten out of international marketplaces by a strong Chinese Yuan as we speak! Oil is next to go! China has acquired the &#8220;South Azadegan Oil fields&#8221; from Iran! This is the largest Oil discovery in thirty years in the Middle East! It did not go to war-like American interests at all! Asians bid for oil world -round and well outside the American admonition that only American dollars be used for oil in the world! The Russians, Chavez and others resent this &#8220;Manipulation&#8221; of oil prices enough to go to war over it. World conditions have changed, even for Yankee Doodle! See: <a href="http://uprooted.jessicareeder.com/2009/09/detroit-and-the-100-dollar-house/comment-page-1/#comment-3003" rel="nofollow">http://uprooted.jessicareeder......mment-3003</a><br />
<a href="http://www.marchandmeffre.com/detroit/index.html" rel="nofollow">http://www.marchandmeffre.com/detroit/index.html</a><br />
to find out what happened to &#8220;Motor City U.S.A.&#8221;  when cheaper Chinese parts in Japanese , Korean and other imported cars were let loose on the American home-markets! China in fact, exports food to the U.S.A.! India mans our computer services by satellite! they send us engineers and do our computer engineering at home in India for us! The Asian onslaught of the larger boned heavier higher calorie, high salary, high upkeep, American is just beginning! The easy resources in America are all gone and we have to change our ways to survive, and this paradigm shift will not be painless! We are about to get our great fattened asses whittled down to size by a very cunning, well educated Asian population, they are at the forefront of change in America, even causing it from their own lands where we cannot do battle with them! The world has shifted, and America is part of the change like it or not.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss><!-- hyper cache 2016-02-09 06:25:05 -->